I'm a contemporary artist
أنا فنان معاصر
with a bit of an unexpected background.
لدي خلفية مختلفة قليلًا
I was in my 20s before I ever went to an art museum.
لم أزر متحفًا فنيًا قبل بلوغ العشرين
I grew up in the middle of nowhere
تربيت في منطقة نائية
on a dirt road in rural Arkansas,
على طريق طيني في ريف أركنساس
an hour from the nearest movie theater.
تبعد أقرب قاعة سينما عنها بساعة
And I think it was a great place to grow up as an artist
وأظنها كانت بيئة مناسبة لنمو فنان
because I grew up around quirky, colorful characters
فقد كبرت وسط شخصيات غنية بالحياة
who were great at making with their hands.
تميزوا بمهاراتهم اليدوية
And my childhood is more hick
وتأثرت طفولتي بالريف
than I could ever possibly relate to you,
لدرجة قد أعجز عن شرحها
and also more intellectual than you would ever expect.
كما تميزت بالفكر بما يفوق توقعاتكم
For instance, me and my sister, when we were little,
فمثلًا، كنت أتسابق مع أختى
we would compete to see who could eat the most squirrel brains.
على التهام مخ السناجب
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But on the other side of that, though,
لكننا على الجانب الآخر
we were big readers in our house.
كان لدينا نهم للقراءة
And if the TV was on, we were watching a documentary.
وإذا شاهدنا التلفاز نفضل فيلمًا وثائقيًا
And my dad is the most voracious reader I know.
وكان أبي أكثر القراء نهمًا
He can read a novel or two a day.
يقرأ رواية أو اثنتين في اليوم
But when I was little, I remember,
لكني أذكر أنه في صغري
he would kill flies in our house with my BB gun.
كان يستخدم مسدسي لقتل الذباب في المنزل
And what was so amazing to me about that --
وما كان يدهشني في هذا الأمر
well he would be in his recliner, would holler for me to fetch the BB gun,
-كان يناديني وهو مستلقيًا لأحضر المسدس
and I'd go get it.
فأحضره-
And what was amazing to me --
أما ما كان يدهشني..
well it was pretty kickass; he was killing a fly in the house with a gun --
كان مذهلًا وهو يطلق النار على الذبابة
but what was so amazing to me
أما ما كان يدهشني حقًا
was that he knew just enough how to pump it.
أنه كان يعرف جيدًا كيف يصوب نحوها
And he could shoot it from two rooms away
ولو كانت على بعد حجرتين منه
and not damage what it was on
دون أن يخرب ما تقف عليه
because he knew how to pump it just enough to kill the fly
لأنه عرف كيف يضغط على الزناد ليقتل حشرة
and not damage what it landed on.
دون تخريب ما حولها
So I should talk about art.
من الأفضل أن أتحدث عن الفن
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Or we'll be here all day with my childhood stories.
وإلا سينقضي اليوم في حكايات طفولتي
I love contemporary art,
أحب الفن المعاصر
but I'm often really frustrated with the contemporary art world
لكن عالم الفن المعاصر يبدو لي محبِطًا
and the contemporary art scene.
وكذلك المشهد الفني المعاصر
A few years ago,
منذ بضع سنوات
I spent months in Europe
قضيت شهورًا في أوروبا
to see the major international art exhibitions
لأتفقد المعارض الفنية العالمية الرائدة
that have the pulse
التي تعد المحرك الأساسي
of what is supposed to be going on in the art world.
لما يجب أن يكون عليه عالم الفن
And I was struck
وتفاجئت..
by going to so many, one after the other,
بزيارة معارض كثيرة
with some clarity of what it was
حيث كانت لدي فكرة واضحة
that I was longing for.
عما أبحث عنه
And I was longing for several things that I wasn't getting,
كنت أبحث عن أشياء كثيرة ولم أجدها
or not getting enough of.
أو لم أجد ما يشبعني منها
But two of the main things:
كنت أفتش عن شيئين ريئيسيين:
one of it, I was longing for more work
أحدهما مزيد من الأعمال..
that was appealing to a broad public,
التي تجذب الجمهور العريض
that was accessible.
وتصل إليهم بسهولة
And the second thing that I was longing for
والشيء الثاني كان
was some more exquisite craftsmanship
المزيد من الحرفية المتقنة
and technique.
والإبداع الفني
So I started thinking and listing
فبدأت أفكر وأدون
what all it was that I thought would make a perfect biennial.
واعتقدت أن أفكاري تصلح لإقامة بينالي كامل
So I decided,
فقررت
I'm going to start my own biennial.
أن أبدأ البينالي الخاص بي
I'm going to organize it and direct it
سأنظمه وأديره
and get it going in the world.
وأنشره في العالم كله
So I thought, okay,
قلت حسنًا
I have to have some criteria of how to choose work.
علي أن أضع معايير لاختيار الأعمال
So amongst all the criteria I have,
ومن بين المعايير كلها
there's two main things.
حددت معيارين أساسيين
One of them, I call my Mimaw's Test.
أولهما أسميته "اختبار جدتي"
And what that is
وأجريه كالتالي
is I imagine explaining a work of art
أتخيل أني أشرح العمل الفني
to my grandmother in five minutes,
لجدتي في خمس دقائق
and if I can't explain it in five minutes,
وإن لم أتمكن من ذلك
then it's too obtuse
فهذا العمل يفتقد الحس الفني
or esoteric
أو يصعب على كل الفئات فهمه
and it hasn't been refined enough yet.
ولم يتم تهذيبه بعد
It needs to worked on
ويحتاج لمزيد من العمل
until it can speak fluently.
حتى يتحدث عن نفسه
And then my other second set of rules --
أما المجموعة الثانية من القواعد
I hate to say "rules" because it's art --
أكره تسميتها "قواعد" لأني أتحدث عن الفن
my criteria would be
المعيار الثاني هو
the three H's,
الأعضاء الثلاثة
which is head, heart and hands.
العقل والقلب واليد
And great art would have "head":
فالفن الرفيع يميزه العقل
it would have interesting intellectual ideas
أي الأفكار والمفاهيم التأملية
and concepts.
المثيرة
It would have "heart" in that it would have passion
ولديه قلب أي تغلب عليه العاطفة
and heart and soul.
قلبًا وروحًا
And it would have "hand" in that it would be greatly crafted.
ولديه يد تمثل الحرفية المتقنة
So I started thinking about
فبدأت أفكر
how am I going to do this biennial,
كيف سأقيم هذا البينالي
how am I going to travel the world
كيف سأسافر حول العالم
and find these artists?
لأجد الفنانين المناسبين
And then I realized one day, there's an easier solution to this.
ثم توصلت إلى حل أسهل
I'm just going to make the whole thing myself.
سأقوم بالأمر كله بنفسي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And so this is what I did.
وهذا ما تم بالفعل
So I thought, a biennial needs artists.
فكرت أن البينالي يحتاج إلى فنانين
I'm going to do an international biennial; I need artists from all around the world.
ولأني أريده عالميًا أحتاج فنانين من حول العالم
So what I did was
فما كان مني
I invented a hundred artists from around the world.
إلا أن اخترعت مائة فنان من حول العالم
I figured out their bios, their passions in life
اخترعت سيرهم الذاتية واهتمامتهم الحياتية
and their art styles,
وأساليبهم الفنية
and I started making their work.
وبدأت في تنفيذ أعمالهم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I felt, oh this is the kind of project that I could spend my whole life doing.
فكرت أني قد أقضي حياتي كلها في مشروع كهذا
So I decided, I'm going to make this a real biennial.
فقررت أن أجعل منه بينالي حقيقي
It's going to be two years of studio work.
عامان من العمل بالاستوديو
And I'm going to create this in two years,
وأنجز كل شيء
and I have.
وقد كان
So I should start to talk about these guys.
لأبدأ بالحديث عن الفنانين
Well the range is quite a bit.
العدد كبير جدًا
And I'm such a technician, so I loved this project,
ولأني مساعد تقني أحببت المشروع
getting to play with all the techniques.
الذي مكنني من التلاعب بالتقنيات
So for example, in realist paintings,
فمثلًا من المدرسة الواقعية
it ranges from this,
تنوعت الأعمال بين هذا
which is kind of old masters style,
بأسلوب الفنانين القدامي
to really realistic still-life,
وتصوير الطبيعة الصامتة
to this type of painting where I'm painting with a single hair.
ولوحات كهذه التي صنعتها بشعرة واحدة
And then at the other end, there's performance and short films
وبين التشخيص والأفلام القصيرة
and indoor installations
والإنشاءات الداخلية
like this indoor installation
كهذا
and this one,
وهذا
and outdoor installations like this one
والإنشاءات الخارجية كهذا
I know I should mention: I'm making all these things.
علي أن أؤكد أني أصنع كل هذا بنفسي
This isn't Photoshopped.
وليس بالفوتوشوب
I'm under the river with those fish.
نزلت لأعماق النهر مع الأسماك
So now let me introduce some of my fictional artists to you.
دعوني أقدم لكم بعض الفنانين الخياليين
This is Nell Remmel.
هذا أحد أعمال (نيل ريميل)
Nell is interested in agricultural processes,
(نيل) مهتمة بالعمليات الزراعية
and her work is based in these practices.
وأعمالها بالأساس في هذا المجال
This piece, which is called "Flipped Earth" --
هذا العمل اسمه "الأرض المقلوبة"
she was interested in taking the sky
أرادت أن تستغل السماء
and using it to cleanse barren ground.
في تطهير الأرض القاحلة
And by taking giant mirrors --
وباستخدام المرايات الضخمة
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
and here she's taking giant mirrors
هنا استخدمت المرايات الضخمة
and pulling them into the dirt.
وأدخلتها في التربة
And this is 22 feet long.
يبلغ طولها 22 قدم
And what I loved about her work
وما أعجبني في عملها هذا
is, when I would walk around it
هو أنني حين أتمشى حوله
and look down into the sky,
وأنظر لأسفل نحو السماء
looking down to watch the sky,
أنظر لأسفل لأشاهدها
and it unfolded in a new way.
تتجلى بطريقة جديدة
And probably the best part of this piece
وربما يظهر جمال هذا العمل
is at dusk and dawn
عند الغسق قبل الفجر
when the twilight wedge has fallen and the ground's dark,
حين يذهب الشفق وتظلم الأرض
but there's still the light above, bright above.
ولا يزال الضوء يلمع في السماء
And so you're standing there and everything else is dark,
فتجلس وكل ما حولك مظلم
but there's this portal that you want to jump in.
إلا هذه البوابة التي ترغب في القفز داخلها
This piece was great. This is in my parents' backyard in Arkansas.
عمل رائع تم بفناء والداي بأركنساس
And I love to dig a hole.
أحب الحفر
So this piece was great fun
وأمتعني هذا العمل
because it was two days of digging in soft dirt.
حيث قضيت يومين أحفر في التربة الناعمة
The next artist is Kay Overstry,
الفنانة التالية هي (كاي أوفيرستري)
and she's interested in ephemerality and transience.
المهتمة بالأعمال المؤقتة الزائلة
And in her most recent project,
وفي أحدث مشروعاتها
it's called "Weather I Made."
"أصنعُ الطقس"
And she's making weather
تقوم بنفسها باستغلال تأثير الطقس
on her body's scale.
على درجة حرارة جسدها
And this piece is "Frost."
هذا العمل بعنوان "صقيع"
And what she did was she went out on a cold, dry night
خرجت في ليلة باردة جافة
and breathed back and forth on the lawn
وأخذت تشهق وتزفر فوق العشب
to leave --
لتترك
to leave her life's mark,
لتترك علامة على وجودها
the mark of her life.
علامة نَفَسها
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And so this is five-foot, five-inches of frost
ويبلغ طوله 5 أقدام، 5 بوصات من الجليد
that she left behind.
قامت بصناعتها
The sun rises, and it melts away.
ثم أشرقت الشمس وذابت
And that was played by my mom.
وأمي هي التي قامت بذلك
So the next artist, this is a group of Japanese artists,
التالي، مجموعة من الفنانين اليابانيين
a collective of Japanese artists --
مجموعة فنانين يابانيين
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
in Tokyo.
في طوكيو
And they were interested in developing a new, alternative art space,
وهم مهتمون بتطوير مساحة فنية بديلة
and they needed funding for it,
وكانوا في حاجة إلى تمويل
so they decided to come up with some interesting fundraising projects.
فقرروا اللجوء لإقامة مشاريع لجمع التبرعات
One of these is scratch-off masterpieces.
أحدها هو التحف المخدوشة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And so what they're doing --
وقاموا بالآتي
each of these artists on a nine-by-seven-inch card,
قام كل فنان بعد توزيع كروت بحجم 9-7 بوصة
which they sell for 10 bucks,
مقابل 10 دولارات
they drew original works of art.
برسم لوحات أصلية
And you buy one, and maybe you get a real piece, and maybe not.
وعند شرائها قد تفوز بلوحة أصلية أو لا
Well this has sparked a craze in Japan,
مما أثار هوس اليابانيين
because everyone's wanting a masterpiece.
فالكل يتمنى الفوز بلوحة أصلية
And the ones that are the most sought after
بينما كانت اللوحات التي رغبوا بها
are the ones that are only barely scratched off.
هي التي ليست بها خدوش كثيرة
And all these works, in some way,
وكانت اللوحات كلها
talk about luck or fate or chance.
تدور حول الحظ أو القدر أو الفرصة
Those first two
هذان العملان
are portraits of mega-jackpot winners years before and after their win.
لفنانين فازا بالجائزة الكبرى، قبل الحدث بسنوات وبعده
And in this one it's called "Drawing the Short Stick."
وهذه اسمها "رسم العصا القصيرة"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I love this piece because I have a little cousin at home
احب هذه اللوحة فابن عمي
who introduced me -- which I think is such a great introduction --
قدمني لأحدهم بأسلوب رائع
to a friend one day as, "This is my cousin Shea.
إلى صديق قائلًا "هذا ابن عمي شيه،
He draws sticks real good."
وهو بارع في رسم العصي."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Which is one of the best compliments ever.
كانت من أجمل المجاملات التي تلقيتها
This artist is Gus Weinmueller,
الفنان (جس وينميلر)
and he's doing a project, a large project, called "Art for the Peoples."
يقيم مشروعًا كبيرًا باسم "الفن للناس"
And within this project, he's doing a smaller project
وضمن هذا المشروع له مشروع أصغر
called "Artists in Residence."
باسم "الفنان المقيم"
And what he does is --
وما يقوم به
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
he spends a week at a time with a family.
هو أنه يقضي أسبوعًا مع أسرة
And he shows up on their porch, their doorstep,
وتجده في شرفتهم وعلى سلالم منزلهم
with a toothbrush and pajamas,
بفرشاة الأسنان مرتديًا البيجامة
and he's ready to spend the week with them.
مستعدًا لقضاء أسبوع معهم
And using only what's present,
وباستخدام ما يتوفر أمامه
he goes in and makes a little abode studio to work out of.
ينشئ استديو إقامة للعمل
And he spends that week talking to the family
وخلال الأسبوع يتحدث مع الأسرة
about what do they think great art is.
عن فكرتهم عن الفن الرفيع
He has all these discussions with their family,
ويطرح الموضوعات للحوار مع أفراد الأسرة
and he digs through everything they have,
ويبحث في أشيائهم
and he finds materials to make work.
ليجد موادًا يصنع منها عملًا فنيًا
And he makes a work
ويقوم بعمل
that answers what they think great art is.
يجيب على السؤال الخاص بفكرتهم عن الفن الرفيع
For this family, he made this still-life painting.
قام برسم هذه اللوحة لهذه الأسرة
And whatever he makes
ومهما كان ما يقوم به
somehow references nesting and space
فهو يشير بشكل ما إلى الدفء المنزلي والمكان
and personal property.
والممتلكات الشخصية
This next project,
المشروع التالي
this is by Jaochim Parisvega,
للفنان (واكيم بيرسفيجا)
and he's interested in --
وهو مهتم بالآتي
he believes art is everywhere waiting --
يؤمن بأن الفن ينتظرنا في كل مكان
that it just needs a little bit of a push to happen.
ولا يحتاج سوى الدفعة الأولى
And he provides this push by harnessing natural forces,
فيقوم هو بهذه الدفعة بتسخير قوى الطبيعة
like in his series where he used rain to make paintings.
كالسلسلة التي استخدم فيها المطر في الرسم
This project is called "Love Nests."
هذا المشروع اسمه "أعشاش الحب"
What he did was to get wild birds to make his art for him.
جعل الطيور البرية تقوم بالعمل الفني بدلًا منه
So he put the material in places where the birds were going to collect them,
فوضع المواد في أماكن متعددة لتجمعها الطيور
and they crafted his nests for him.
فقاموا ببناء الأعشاش
And this one's called "Lovelock's Nest."
هذا اسمه "عش خصلة الحب"
This one's called "Mixtape Love Song's Nest."
وهذا "عش أغاني الحب"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And this one's called "Lovemaking Nest."
وهذا "عش الجنس"
Next is Sylvia Slater.
الفنانة التالية هي (سلفيا سلاتر)
Sylvia's interested in art training.
سلفيا مهتمة بتعليم الفن
She's a very serious Swiss artist.
فنانة سويسرية جادة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And she was thinking about her friends and family
كانت تفكر بأصدقائها وعائلتها
who work in chaos-ridden places and developing countries,
الذين يعملون بالمناطق التي تعمها الفوضى والبلاد النامية
and she was thinking,
وفكرت
what can I make that would be of value to them,
فيما يمكن أن يشكل قيمة لهم
in case something bad happens
في حالة حدوث كارثة
and they have to buy their way across the border
تضطرهم للدفع مقابل عبور الحدود
or pay off a gunman?
أو رشوة رجل مسلح
And so she came up with creating
فتوصلت إلى تنفيذ..
these pocket-sized artworks
أعمال فنية بحجم الجيب
that are portraits of the person that would carry them.
عبارة عن صورة لمن يحملها
And you would carry this around with you,
فتحمل شئ كهذا معك
and if everything went to hell, you could make payments
وإذا دُمر كل شئ يمكنك الدفع
and buy your life.
لشراء حياتك
So this life price
وثمن الحياة هذا
is for an irrigation non-profit director.
لمدير ري لا يهدف للربح
So hopefully what happens is you never use it,
على أمل ألا يحدث ما يضطرك لاستخدامه
and it's an heirloom that you pass down.
وتورثه لمن بعدك
And she makes them so they could either be broken up into payments,
وهي مصنوعة بحيث يمكن كسرها لتقسيمها
or they could be like these, which are leaves that can be payments.
أو كهذه، أوراق شجر يمكن تقديمها كما هي
And so they're valuable. This is precious metals and gemstones.
ولذا تعتبر قيمة. هذه مصنوعة من معادن وأحجار كريمة
And this one had to get broken up.
وهذه لزم كسرها
He had to break off a piece to get out of Egypt recently.
اضطر صاحبها لكسر قطعة للخروج من مصر مؤخرًا
This is by a duo, Michael Abernathy and Bud Holland.
هذا العمل للثنائي (مايكل أبيرناثي) و (بد هولاند)
And they're interested in creating culture,
المهتم بخلق الثقافة
just tradition.
كتقليد جديد
So what they do is they move into an area
فينتقلا إلى منطقة
and try to establish a new tradition in a small geographic area.
ويحاولا ابتداع تقليد جديد في مساحة جغرافية صغيرة
So this is in Eastern Tennessee,
تم هذا في شرق تينيسي
and what they decided was
حيث قررا..
that we need a positive tradition
أننا نحتاج تقليدًا إيجابيًا
that goes with death.
يتعلق بالموت
So they came up with "dig jigs."
فتوصلا إلى رقصة الحفر
And a dig jig --
ورقصة الحفر هي
for a milestone anniversary or a birthday,
في ذكرى حدث هام أو عيد ميلاد
you gather all your friends and family together
تجمع كل أصدقائك وأفراد عائلتك
and you dance on where you're going to be buried.
وترقص في المكان الذي ستدفن فيه
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And we got a lot of attention when we did it.
التجربة جذبت انتباه الكثيرين
I talked my family into doing this, and they didn't know what I was doing.
أقنعت أسرتي، ولم يكونوا يعرفوا بمشروعي
And I was like, "Get dressed for a funeral. We're going to go do some work."
فقلت "ارتدوا ملابسكم لنذهب إلى جنازة، لدينا عمل."
And so we got to the grave and made this, which was hilarious --
فذهبنا إلى مقابر وقمنا بذلك،
the attention that we got.
ولاقينا اهتمامًا كبيرًا
So what happens is you dance on the grave,
تتم التجربة بأن ترقص عند القبر
and after you've done your dance,
وبعد أن تنهي رقصتك
everyone toasts you and tells you how great you are.
يشرب الجميع نخبك ويشيدوا برقصك
And you in essence have a funeral
بينما أنت في جنازة
that you get to be present for.
عليك حضورها
That's my mom and dad.
هذان أمي وأبي
This is by Jason Birdsong.
هذا العمل للفنان (جاسون بيردسونج)
He is interested in how we see as an animal,
المهتم برؤيتنا للحيوان
how we are interested in mimicry and camouflage.
وفضولنا حول المحاكاة والتمويه
You know, we look down a dark alley
فعندما ننظر إلى ممر مظلم
or a jungle path,
أو طريق في غابة
trying to make out a face or a creature.
نحاول ملاحظة وجه أو مخلوق
We just have that natural way of seeing.
فنحن نستخدم طريقتنا الطبيعية في الرؤية
And he plays with this idea.
وهو يستغل هذه الفكرة
And this piece: those aren't actually leaves.
وهذا العمل؛ هذه ليست أوراق حقيقية
They're butterfly specimens who have a natural camouflage.
وإنما نوع من الفراشات يتميز بالتمويه الطبيعي
So he pairs these up.
فأضاف لها
There's another pile of leaves.
-هناك كومة أخرى من الأوراق
Those are actually all real butterfly specimens.
كلها فراشات حقيقية-
And he pairs these up with paintings.
أضاف لها الرسومات
Like this is a painting of a snake in a box.
كهذه اللوحة لثعبان في صندوق
So you open the box and you think, "Whoa, there's a snake in there."
فتفتح الصندوق وتتفاجأ قائلًا "يوجد ثعبان في الصندوق"
But it's actually a painting.
لكنها مجرد لوحة
So he makes these interesting conversations
وبذلك تدور الحوارات الشيقة
about realism and mimicry
حول الواقع والمحاكاة
and our drive to be fooled by great camouflage.
ودوافع انخداعنا بالتمويه المتقن
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The next artist is Hazel Clausen.
الفنانة التالية هي (هازل كلوسين)
Hazel Clausen is an anthropologist who took a sabbatical
(هازل كلوسين) هي عالمة إنسانيات تفرغت
and decided, "You know, I would learn a lot about culture
وقررت "سأتعلم الكثير عن الثقافة
if I created a culture that doesn't exist from scratch."
إذا ابتدعت ثقافة لا وجود لها."
So that's what she did.
وهو ما قامت به
She created the Swiss people named the Uvulites,
اخترعت جماعة سويسرية أسمتها "الحلقيون"
and they have this distinctive yodeling song
المعروفون بأغنيتهم المميزة
that they use the uvula for.
التي يستخدمون لهاة الحلق لغنائها
And also they reference how the uvula --
كما يُرجعون أن لهاة الحلق
everything they say is fallen
تجعل الكلام منخفضًا
because of the forbidden fruit.
إلى الفاكهة المحرمة
And that's the symbol of their culture.
وهي رمز ثقافتهم
And this is from a documentary
وهذه الصورة من فيلم وثائقي
called "Sexual Practices and Populations Control
بعنوان "الممارسات الجنسية وتحديد النسل
Among the Uvulites."
عند الحلقيين."
This is a typical angora embroidery for them.
وهذا تطريز بصوف المُهير الذي اشتهروا به
This is one of their founders, Gert Schaeffer.
هذه من مؤسسي الجماعة (جيرت شيفر)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And actually this is my Aunt Irene.
وفي الواقع هي عمتي (إيرين)
It was so funny having a fake person
وكان طريفًا اختراع شخص خيالي
who was making fake things.
يخترع أشياء خيالية
And I crack up at this piece,
وهذه بالتحديد تضحكني بشدة
because when I see it I know that's French angora
لأني أعرف أن هذا من الصوف الفرنسي
and all antique German ribbons
والشرائط ألمانية
and wool that I got in a Nebraska mill
والصوف أيضًا اشتريته من مصنع في نبراسكا
and carried around for 10 years
منذ 10 سنوات
and then antique Chinese skirts.
والتنورات صينية قديمة
The next is a collective of artists
والمشروع التالي لجماعة فنية
called the Silver Dobermans,
باسم "سيلفر دوبرمان"
and their motto is to spread pragmatism
وشعارهم هو نشر البراجماتية
one person at a time.
بواسطة واحد منهم في كل مرة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And they're really interested
وتشغلهم فكرة..
in how over-coddled we've become.
كيف أصبحنا مدللين أكثر من اللازم
So this is one of their comments on how over-coddled we've become.
وهذا أحد تعليقاتهم حول هذه الفكرة
And what they've done
فما كان منهم إلا أن
is they put a warning sign on every single barb on this fence.
وضعوا لافتة تحذيرية على كل شوكة في السياج
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And this is called "Horse Sense Fence."
وأسموه "سياج الفطرة السليمة"
The next artist is K. M. Yoon,
التالي هو الفنان (كيه إم يون)
a really interesting South Korean artist.
فنان متميز من كوريا الجنوبية
And he's reworking a Confucian art tradition
يعمل على إعادة إحياء تقليد فني كونفوشيوسي
of scholar stones.
من الأحجار
Next is Maynard Sipes.
التالي هو (ماينارد سايبس)
And I love Maynard Sipes,
وأنا معجب بماينارد بشدة
but he's off in his own world,
لكنه منغلق في عالمه الخاص
and, bless his heart, he's so paranoid.
وأتمنى له الشفاء فهو مريض بالبارانويا
Next is Roy Penig,
التالي هو (روي بينيج)
a really interesting Kentucky artist,
فنان متميز من ولاية كنتاكي
and he's the nicest guy.
وهو شخص لطيف جدًا
He even once traded a work of art for a block of government cheese
ففي مرة باع عملاً مقابل قطعة جبن مما توزعه الحكومة
because the person wanted it so badly.
لأن الرجل كان يريده بشدة
Next is an Australian artist, Janeen Jackson,
التالية هي الأسترالية (جنين جاكسون)
and this is from a project of hers
وهذا أحد أعمال مشروعها
called "What an Artwork Does When We're Not Watching."
واسمه "ما يفعله العمل الفني في غيابنا"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Next is by a Lithuanian fortune teller, Jurgi Petrauskas.
التالي لعراف لتواني اسمه (جورجي بيتروسكاس)
Next is Ginger Cheshire.
والتالي للفنان (جينجر تشيشر)
This is from a short film of hers called "The Last Person."
وهو من فيلم قصير بعنوان "الأخير"
And that's my cousin and my sister's dog, Gabby.
وهذه ابنة عمي مع (جابي) الكلب الخاص بأختي
The next, this is by Sam Sandy.
وهذا للفنان (سام ساندي)
He's an Australian Aboriginal elder,
وهو من السكان الأصليين لأستراليا
and he's also an artist.
وهو فنان أيضًا
And this is from a large traveling sculpture project
وهذا جزء من مشروع تجوالي كبير للنحت
that he's doing.
يقوم به
This is from Estelle Willoughsby.
وهذا للفنانة (إستيل ويلسبي)
She heals with color.
التي تعالج باستخدام الألوان
And she's one of the most prolific of all these hundred artists,
وهي واحدة من أكثرهم غزارة في الإنتاج
even though she's going to be 90 next year.
رغم أنها ستبلغ الـ 90 في العام المقبل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is by Z. Zhou,
وهذا للفنان (زي زو)
and he's interested in stasis.
وهو مهتم بفكرة الثباث
Next is by Hilda Singh,
التالي للفنانة (هيلدا سينج)
and she's doing a whole project called "Social Outfits."
ولها مشروع كامل بعنوان "المظهر الاجتماعي"
Next is by Vera Sokolova.
وهذا للفنانة (فيرا سوكولوفا)
And I have to say, Vera kind of scares me.
وعلى أن أخبركم أنها تخيفني
You can't look her directly in the eyes
فلا يمكن النظر في عينيها مباشرة
because she's kind of scary.
لأنها مرعبة حقًا
And it's good that she's not real;
ومن الجيد أنها شخصية خيالية
she'd be mad that I said that.
كانت ستغضب من كلامي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And she's an optometrist in St. Petersburg,
هي طبيبة عيون في سانت بطرسبرغ
and she plays with optics.
وتهتم في عملها بالبصريات
Next, this is by Thomas Swifton.
التالي هو (توماس سويفتون)
This is from a short film, "Adventures with Skinny."
وهذه من فيلمه القصير "مغامرات نحيف"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And this is by Cicily Bennett,
وهذه للفنانة (سيسيلي بينيت)
and it's from a series of short films.
من سلسلة أفلام قصيرة
And after this one, there's 77 other artists.
وغير هؤلاء يوجد 77 فنانًا
And all together with those other 77 you're not seeing,
وبكل من شاهدتم أعمالهم مع الـ 77 الآخرين
that's my biennial.
أقمت البينالي الخاص بي
Thank you. Thank you.
شكرًا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you. Thanks.
أشكركم